<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Down &amp; Output</title>
    <link>https://downandoutput.com/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Down &amp; Output</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>chanunnaki@gmail.com (Chanunnaki)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>chanunnaki@gmail.com (Chanunnaki)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 14:49:14 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://downandoutput.com/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>⌘ macOS Color Pickers</title>
      <link>https://downandoutput.com/posts/mac-color-pickers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 14:49:14 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>chanunnaki@gmail.com (Chanunnaki)</author>
      <guid>https://downandoutput.com/posts/mac-color-pickers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In nature, light creates the color. In the picture, color creates the light.&lt;br /&gt;
-&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hans_Hofmann&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hans Hoffman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colors… they&amp;rsquo;re everywhere and all around us, and don’t you just love them? When designing anything, colors are super important. The color of your fonts and UI elements can give your creations unique personality, character and drive attention towards different aspects of your design. Colors also give designers the ability to subtly draw a users’ focus to a desired element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, I knew I really needed to up my color game, so I started looking into the current color-picking app landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many, many apps out there today focused on helping designers pick colors and these apps normally have built-in functionality for choosing, picking, storing individual colors and creating or maintaining color palettes. These apps also make it easy for you to export your colors in a variety of usable formats, such as CSS HEX, Swift/NSColor, RGB, CMYK, Android or even Pantone color formats for use in your development environment such as Xcode or your design package of choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is a table of some of the best color pickers in the macOS app ecosystem today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;App&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Mac App Store?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nscoding.co.uk&#34;&gt;Color Picker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/color-picker/&#34;&gt;Yes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;$3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://colorsnapper.com&#34;&gt;ColorSnapper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/colorsnapper/id969418666&#34;&gt;Yes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;$9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://colorslurp.com&#34;&gt;ColorSlurp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/colorslurp/id1287239339?mt=12&#34;&gt;Yes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Free (w/ IAP)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rimbunesia.com/apps/kelir-color-picker-for-mac/&#34;&gt;Kelir&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/kelir-simple-yet-powerful/id1145215534?mt=12&#34;&gt;Yes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Free (w/ IAP)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pikkaapp.com&#34;&gt;Pikka&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pikka-color-picker/id1195076754&#34;&gt;Yes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;$7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried them all yet, and this isn&amp;rsquo;t an exhaustive list by any stretch of the imagination but in this article, I&amp;rsquo;d like to highlight just two of the best color-picking apps I’ve tried recently: &lt;a href=&#34;https://sipapp.io/&#34;&gt;Sip&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cusaro.it/aquarelo/&#34;&gt;Aquarelo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sip&#34;&gt;Sip&lt;/h2&gt;


  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/sip_icon.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Sip App Icon&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px; width: 256px;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Sip App Icon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This app has a very nice interface and boasts a wonderful contrast checking feature, I found this feature most interesting and is probably my favourite feature of the app. Input two colors, and the checker will give you a score based on the relative contrast between those two colors.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/1.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Check Contrast in Sip&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Check Contrast in Sip&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If the contrast of your two colors gets a low score, you can quickly click on “FIX” and — as the button name implies — Sip will give you a new color of a similar hue that will increase the contrast for maximum legibility.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/1.1.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Sip Magnifier and Color Name&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Sip Magnifier and Color Name&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;h2 id=&#34;aquarelo&#34;&gt;Aquarelo&lt;/h2&gt;


  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/aqua_icon.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Aquarelo App Icon&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;  width: 256px;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Aquarelo App Icon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Moving onto Aquarelo, you can see the interface is very unique, highly minimalist and it reminds me of the color swatches you can pick up at the paint store.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/2.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Aquarelo UI&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px; border-style: solid; border-width: 8px; border-color : #191926; background-color: #191926;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Aquarelo UI&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I would say Aquarelo is the more elegant and beautifully designed of the two, but I think they serve slightly different audiences. I can see Aquarello being very good fit for interior or fashion designers, where you might need a range shades between two colors you have already chosen, whereas Sip perhaps caters more towards the experimental, promoting a freer spirit of mixing and matching.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/2.1.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Aquarelo Pantone-esque&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px; border-style: solid; border-width: 8px; border-color : #191926; background-color: #191926;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Aquarelo Pantone-esque&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Both these apps allow you to export your palettes as HTML files. I put the same palette of colors into both apps and exported it as a demonstration. You can check out the results &lt;a href=&#34;https://downandoutput.com/palette_sip.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (Sip) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://downandoutput.com/palette_aquarello.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (Aquarelo). One thing to note is that both of these apps produced completely different names for the same colors, which might surprise you, but the names are really only used to add character to the colors, as opposed to being reliable indentifiers in and of themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cost-and-trials&#34;&gt;Cost and Trials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Costing $10 and $13 respectively, these color apps are useful and beautifully designed, and while I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t consider them expensive, they are the most expensive of all the premium color pickers that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen and it probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to pay for one of these apps unless you know you&amp;rsquo;ll be using it very regularly. To find out for yourself which you might like, it makes sense to download them and try for yourself - Sip has a free trial available from their site, Aquarelo does not, but you can trial both of these apps as part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://setapp.com/&#34;&gt;SetApp&lt;/a&gt;. And while Aquarelo is available on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/aquareloapp&#34;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;, Sip is not, available instead exclusively through their own homepage and SetApp. It was through SetApp that I trialled Aquarelo myself while I downloaded Sip as a trial directly from their homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mostly loved everything about both the apps but one complaint I would have about Sip is that I found the high frequency of their reminders to purchase their product and how many days were left of my trial to border on the obnoxious. Every time I logged into my Mac or woke up from sleep, I’d get a reminder. Sometimes I got these notifications for zero apparent reason, interrupting what I was doing. This got old very quickly and I deleted the app after a small number of days. That&amp;rsquo;s quite a minor complaint though if I were actually using their app on a daily basis, like probably most of their target audience would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving-on&#34;&gt;Moving On&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, I didn’t stick with either of these apps. I felt that they were a little beyond the scope of my needs. You might feel differently yourself because maybe you’re a professional full-time designer, or perhaps you work as part of a team or as a design lead, but I am not. I just need a simple way to pick a color every now and again. So in the end, I couldn’t really justify the cost, and I could do without yet-another icon in my [already-saturated] status bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I was reminded consistently of Apple’s own built-in Color Picker. This comes as standard in Mac OS X and is itself quite sophisticated. You will have seen it residing inside many other apps you use on a daily basis, such as Apple’s own software like Pages or Numbers. It should be noted that both Sip and Aquarelo give you an option to open up Apple&amp;rsquo;s built-in color picker from within their respective apps. This is most important for Aquarelo, because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually have it&amp;rsquo;s own custom color picker tool.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/3.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Apple&amp;#39;s Color Picker&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Apple&amp;#39;s Standard Color Picker&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Out of all the pickers I&amp;rsquo;ve tested, this one is really my favourite one of all, because it’s a known quantity and it focuses purely on the task of picking and saving colors very efficiently and effectively. Not only that, it can be extended with extensions, like with this wonderful color picker extension that goes by the name of &lt;a href=&#34;https://bjango.com/mac/skalacolor/&#34;&gt;Skala Color&lt;/a&gt;, made by one of my favourite software houses – &lt;a href=&#34;https://bjango.com/&#34;&gt;Bjango&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/4.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Skala Color UI&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px; border-style: solid; border-width: 8px; border-color : #191926; background-color: #191926;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Skala Color UI&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It too has the ability to export your colors in many formats, as you can see in the following screengrab.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/5.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Skala Color Export Options&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px; border-style: solid; border-width: 8px; border-color : #191926; background-color: #191926;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Skala Color Export Options&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Skala Color has a really beautiful, high-precision color picker and does almost everything I need it to do, and the best part of all? It’s absolutely free.
I must say, Apple Color Picker with the Skala Color extension is really a fantastic combination and this would be my first recommendation to anyone who needs an exceedingly useful [&lt;strong&gt;free!&lt;/strong&gt;] color picker for their development or designing needs. This combination is not really lacking in any way except for being slightly less intuitive than the paid apps, but in terms of functionality: it&amp;rsquo;s all here. Personally, I don’t really mind just managing my palettes manually in the handy built-in color wells.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/6.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Practically Limitless&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Practically Limitless&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can go a step further and create as many custom palettes as you want. Again, it&amp;rsquo;s not as intuitive or beautiful as the paid apps, but it&amp;rsquo;s more than sufficient. While I usually maintain my color palettes within design apps such as Sketch or Illustrator, it&amp;rsquo;s certainly handy to have them in here so they can be called upon at any time.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/6.1.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Custom Palette&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Custom Palette&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To take it further again, you can download more color palettes and add them to Apple&amp;rsquo;s Color Picker. What you need to look for are palette files which carry the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;.clr&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; extension and put them into your &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;~/Library/Colors&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; folder. Then they will be available to you next time you open the color picker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got a complete set of Pantone Swatches in mine.

  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/6.2.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Pantone Swatches&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Pantone Swatches&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These Pantone palette files were expertly crafted by Midwinter Duncan Grant and can be downloaded from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.midwinter-dg.com/resources.html#color-palettes&#34;&gt;Resources page&lt;/a&gt; of his site for free. Midwinter makes available a lot more free goodies beyond color palettes too, so be sure to check out his site &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.midwinter-dg.com&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mapdiva.com/&#34;&gt;Mapdiva&lt;/a&gt; also have a list of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mapdiva.com/artboard/artb-tutorial/12-custom-color-palettes-for-macos/&#34;&gt;12 Custom Color Palettes&lt;/a&gt; for you to download. I did find some of the links here broken, but it&amp;rsquo;s a good article nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you&amp;rsquo;re specifically a coder and also have in interest in colors, I recommend you take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ethanschoonover.com/&#34;&gt;Ethan Schoonover&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ethanschoonover.com/solarized&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Solarized&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; project. This is a palette of only 16 colours, but they are highly refined, precise and tested extensively for contrast and legibility across many text editors and devices in a variety of lighting conditions. Basically, if you&amp;rsquo;re a coder, you owe it to yourself [and your eyes] to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-last-thing&#34;&gt;One Last Thing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Apple’s Color Picker with Bjango&amp;rsquo;s Skala Color, that sounds like a real killer combo, right? Yes, but there is one major caveat: normally, you can only access Apple’s Color Picker within other apps and not as a standalone app that can be launched like any standard app.
This would seem to limit its function somewhat for picking colors when you’re browsing the Internet, for example. But fear not, you can easily turn Apple’s Color Picker into a standalone app that can be accessed and launched at any time, no matter what you’re doing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is done through a very simple AppleScript, made with Apple’s Script Editor, which you can find in the &lt;code&gt;Utilities&lt;/code&gt; folder in your &lt;code&gt;~/Applications&lt;/code&gt; directory. You can follow a very handy guide &lt;a href=&#34;http://hints.macworld.com/article.php?story=20060408050920158&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;Mac OS X Hints&lt;/em&gt; if you need further details, but should you want something even easier, I have gone ahead and made this handy app available for you to download for free. There are two version, one for speakers of British English, and the other in US-English. Just click download below to grab one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
Colors.app [750KB] &lt;a href=&#34;./files/Colors.zip&#34;&gt;DOWNLOAD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Colours.app [750KB] &lt;a href=&#34;./files/Colours.zip&#34;&gt;DOWNLOAD&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/7.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Colors or Colours, Pick Your Poison&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Colors or Colours, Pick Your Poison&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The icon I used is by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iconarchive.com/artist/mcdo-design.html&#34;&gt;Susumu Yoshida&lt;/a&gt;. I hope you enjoy it and find it suitable for your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have yourself a wonderfully colorful day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: If you&amp;rsquo;d like to know how to change the icon of any App, File or Folder on macOS, check out this small guide &lt;a href=&#34;https://downandoutput.com/posts/change-mac-icons/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>

    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

