<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Down &amp; Output</title>
    <link>https://downandoutput.com/tags/playstation/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Down &amp; Output</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>chanunnaki@gmail.com (Chanunnaki)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>chanunnaki@gmail.com (Chanunnaki)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 21:36:18 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://downandoutput.com/tags/playstation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>🎮 The Future of Playstation</title>
      <link>https://downandoutput.com/posts/playstation-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 21:36:18 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>chanunnaki@gmail.com (Chanunnaki)</author>
      <guid>https://downandoutput.com/posts/playstation-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wired have just published an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/exclusive-sony-next-gen-console/&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; with comments from Playstation lead system architect Mark Cerny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PlayStation’s next-generation console ticks all those boxes, starting with an AMD chip at the heart of the device. (Warning: some alphabet soup follows.) The CPU is based on the third generation of AMD’s Ryzen line and contains eight cores of the company’s new 7nm Zen 2 microarchitecture. The GPU, a custom variant of Radeon’s Navi family, will support ray tracing, a technique that models the travel of light to simulate complex interactions in 3D environments. While ray tracing is a staple of Hollywood visual effects and is beginning to worm its way into $10,000 high-end processors, no game console has been able to manage it. Yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that Sony have decided to use Wired.com as a platform to announce the first details of their next console. I think this is a good move on their part. Moving beyond the typical gaming-press, they have the potential to access a broader audience this way. Smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I won&amp;rsquo;t go into the details of our VR strategy today,” he says, “beyond saying that VR is very important to us and that the current PSVR headset is compatible with the new console.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very shrewd of Sony to continue supporting their first-generation of VR hardware with their next console. This might put people&amp;rsquo;s mind at ease with their current investment and further investment into software for the current iteration. I think this is also a very strong indication that BC (Backwards Compatibility) with PS4 software is shoe-in for the next generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cerny claims that it has a raw bandwidth higher than any SSD available for PCs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazing. Super-SSD confirmed for PS5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it’s based in part on the PS4’s architecture, it will also be backward-compatible with games for that console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, BC confirmed also. I&amp;rsquo;m now ready and excited  for a new console generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Via: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/exclusive-sony-next-gen-console/&#34;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt;. Paid subscription (possibly) required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>

    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

