<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Down &amp; Output</title>
    <link>https://downandoutput.com/tags/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Down &amp; Output</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>chanunnaki@gmail.com (Chanunnaki)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>chanunnaki@gmail.com (Chanunnaki)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 17:06:20 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://downandoutput.com/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>⌨︎ Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://downandoutput.com/posts/hugo-tut-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 17:06:20 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>chanunnaki@gmail.com (Chanunnaki)</author>
      <guid>https://downandoutput.com/posts/hugo-tut-one/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In the first part of this three-part series, I&amp;rsquo;ll guide you in setting up a simple blog like the one you&amp;rsquo;re on right now, and show you how to host it for free on Github Pages. When I began on this journey myself, I had close to zero experience with Github. I followed some of the available guides already out there on the web, (including those from Hugo themselves), but there were some parts that didn’t quite click with me right away and it relied upon a lot of time and trial &amp;amp; error before it all finally worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this series, I will assume you have close-to-zero experience with setting up websites or with Github, but by the end, I hope you will understand exactly how to work with Hugo, and understanding more clearly some of the broader concepts in using Git, and then finally, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to customise your site, and create the workflow for pushing content out to your blog in a quick &amp;amp; efficient manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: This guide is written from the perspective of a Mac user, but the general workflow should be the same across all platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-hugo&#34;&gt;Why Hugo?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always wanted to write my own blog since the early days of the internet, but none of the available platforms appealed to me. I really didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use a &amp;ldquo;pre-rolled&amp;rdquo; solution like Blogger.com due to lack of customisation and Wordpress just felt &lt;em&gt;too much&lt;/em&gt;. What I always needed and wanted was something in between those two extremes and &lt;em&gt;Hugo&lt;/em&gt; is it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hugo&lt;/em&gt; is a static website generator with theming support as opposed to a dynamic site generator like &lt;em&gt;Wordpress&lt;/em&gt;. This means that instead of your site being generated on-the-fly from a database, all your pages are served as plain HTML and CSS. It also means that your site is delivered to the end-user blazingly fast. I loved the idea of generating static sites again, bringing me back to the earlier days of site creation and that Do-It-Yourself feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did try operating a &lt;em&gt;Wordpress&lt;/em&gt; site on multiple occasions in the past and while it’s easy to set up, I found the main aspects of its customisation to be utterly incomprehensible and I consider it to be — putting it lightly — hugely bloated. There are also many costs involved if you want to engage with any of the customisation options available in the form of themes or plugins. Not to mention the costs involved in procuring a domain and hosting of the site, backed by a full-blown database. Due to these factors, my desire to operate a blog actually fell by the wayside for a number of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paying for hosting is not something I wanted to do as I’m not expecting to generate an income from my blog. Instead, it’s a place for me to gather my thoughts and share some interesting ideas and information. Hosting in general isn’t cheap for a Wordpress site, even though the software itself is free and open-source, the hosting alone could easily end up costing you hundreds of dollars per year. This immediately puts you under pressure to monetise your blog instead of just focusing on the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I found out you can host your static site on Github Pages for free, delivering pages to the user from Github&amp;rsquo;s fast SSDs, I was completely sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speed of content delivery to the end user through the use of static is pages is one of Hugo&amp;rsquo;s greatest strengths, and while I&amp;rsquo;m aware that there are numerous plugins available on &lt;em&gt;Wordpress&lt;/em&gt; that aim to pre-compile pages for faster delivery &amp;ndash; and this is a very valid point in favour of &lt;em&gt;Wordpress&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ndash; I still never did feel confident in relying upon Wordpress as the foundation for my site. Of course, I may be in the minority here, because Wordpress drives a massive percentage of all the sites across the internet, but for a simple blog like this one, &lt;em&gt;Wordpress&lt;/em&gt; is most certainly &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;overkill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, enough about all that, you&amp;rsquo;re probably here because you already know you&amp;rsquo;d like to have a static site, so we&amp;rsquo;ll move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;firstly&#34;&gt;Firstly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Quick Start&lt;/em&gt; guide from &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; is actually quite good, so much of the information from that guide will be re-iterated here. If you are already comfortable with the Terminal or already have your Hugo site set up, you may not need this part of the tutorial at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin, the very first thing you want to do is open up your Terminal (AKA CLI). You can do this by pressing &lt;code&gt;cmd + space&lt;/code&gt; on your keyboard to bring up Spotlight Search, and begin typing &lt;code&gt;terminal&lt;/code&gt;. When the application shows, just press &lt;code&gt;enter&lt;/code&gt; and up pops the Terminal.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/1.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Terminal Window&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px; &#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Terminal Window&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in why my Terminal may look slightly differently to yours, please refer to the &lt;em&gt;bonus tip&lt;/em&gt; at the end of the article: &lt;a href=&#34;http://downandoutput.com/posts/terminal-tutorial/&#34;&gt;Terminal Navigation 101&lt;/a&gt;. You will also find some other hints and tips for getting started with Terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything in Hugo is done through the Terminal (AKA CLI), so it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to get yourself familiarised with this application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-install-homebrew-hugo&#34;&gt;1. Install Homebrew &amp;amp; Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install Hugo, you first need to install a package manager. &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Homebrew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the name of the package manager we&amp;rsquo;re using here. Just copy and paste the following code into Terminal&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;/usr/bin/ruby -e &amp;quot;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/install)&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then press &lt;code&gt;enter&lt;/code&gt; to begin installation, and wait for the installation to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When that&amp;rsquo;s done, it&amp;rsquo;s time to install Hugo. This is done by typing the following into Terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;brew install hugo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-create-your-site&#34;&gt;2. Create Your Site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to assume you&amp;rsquo;re in your &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt; directory, but if you want to create your site elsewhere, just navigate there. Again, you can refer to &lt;a href=&#34;http://downandoutput.com/posts/terminal-tutorial/&#34;&gt;Terminal Navigation 101&lt;/a&gt; to understand this better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a new site called &amp;ldquo;blog&amp;rdquo; (you can call it whatever you want) just enter this command into Terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;hugo new site blog
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just like that, your new site is created. Now, if you navigate to your &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt; folder in &lt;code&gt;Finder&lt;/code&gt;, you will see a new folder called &amp;ldquo;blog&amp;rdquo; there. This is where all the code and files of your site resides.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/2.png&#34;  alt=&#34;New Site Folder&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px; &#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;New Site Folder&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is just a raw template for your site right now, and [in theory] if you go to the site in your browser, you&amp;rsquo;ll see nothing but a blank page. So, you need to add a theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-add-a-theme&#34;&gt;3. Add a Theme&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add a theme, you first need to visit the following website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io&#34;&gt;themes.gohugo.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you find the theme you want to use, you need to copy the &lt;code&gt;Download&lt;/code&gt; URL from the &lt;code&gt;Download&lt;/code&gt; button on the theme&amp;rsquo;s homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/hermit/&#34;&gt;Hermit&lt;/a&gt; theme.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;img/hugo_theme.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Hermit Theme&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px; &#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;color: white;&#34; &gt;Hermit Theme&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The URL from the &lt;code&gt;Download&lt;/code&gt; button is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Track3/hermit.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: This URL ends in &lt;code&gt;.git&lt;/code&gt;. This is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve got this URL, &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into the &lt;code&gt;blog/&lt;/code&gt; directory you just created by using this command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;cd blog/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now comes your first interaction with &lt;em&gt;Git&lt;/em&gt; through the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Recent versions of macOS have an Apple fork of Git already installed as standard. If your installation doesn&amp;rsquo;t have this, type &lt;code&gt;brew install git&lt;/code&gt; and wait for the installation to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Type into Terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;git init
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and press &lt;code&gt;enter&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;git submodule add https://github.com/Track3/hermit.git themes/hermit
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What these two commands are doing is first initialising a local Git respository based on your &lt;code&gt;blog&lt;/code&gt; folder and then you&amp;rsquo;re adding a &amp;ldquo;submodule&amp;rdquo; of the theme into your &lt;code&gt;themes&lt;/code&gt; folder. A submodule is Git&amp;rsquo;s way of creating a copy of a respository within another respository, which in this case, is your site folder: &lt;code&gt;blog&lt;/code&gt;. This makes it very easy for you to keep the theme up to date by updating the submodule, but what we&amp;rsquo;re doing here now is just taking an &lt;em&gt;image&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;clone&lt;/em&gt; of your chosen theme and copying it into your &lt;code&gt;/themes/&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final step in using this theme is by following the instructions in the &lt;code&gt;readme.md&lt;/code&gt; file included with the theme you just downloaded. Every theme will include a &lt;code&gt;readme.md&lt;/code&gt; file with basic installation instructions, and this theme is no different. You&amp;rsquo;re asked to copy the &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; from the theme&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;exampleSite&lt;/code&gt; folder into the root of your Hugo site. You can do this manually through &lt;code&gt;Finder&lt;/code&gt; or just simply use the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;cp themes/hermit/exampleSite/config.toml .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NB: Be sure you copy the whole command, including the &lt;code&gt;space + .&lt;/code&gt; at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; is where you configure your site&amp;rsquo;s title, copyright information, etc. This last command will replace the default &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; file with the custom one from the theme. You could take a look inside this file right now, and make your own customisations, but I recommend doing that later, once you&amp;rsquo;re finished with this tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-create-a-post&#34;&gt;4. Create a Post&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can quickly create a new post for your blog through the CLI by using the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;hugo new posts/my-first-post.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This creates a file called &lt;code&gt;my-first-post.md&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;/blog/content/posts/&lt;/code&gt; and is your actual blog post. You can edit this file with any regular text editor, such as &lt;code&gt;TextEdit&lt;/code&gt;.
All the custom content you create for your site will reside in this &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; file extension means this is a &lt;em&gt;markdown&lt;/em&gt; file. Markdown is a very simple and lightweight markup language that easily lets you format your blog posts with very minimal syntax, through any plain text editor. &lt;em&gt;Hugo&lt;/em&gt; uses markdown extensively to format your posts. Getting into markdown is beyond the scope of this article, but there are many guides elsewhere online for you to learn markdown. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/wiki/Markdown-Cheatsheet&#34;&gt;Markdown Cheatsheet&lt;/a&gt; is one such example for a quick reference on markdown. The standard-bearing documentation at &lt;a href=&#34;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;Daring Fireball&lt;/a&gt; is also highly recommended reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-start-the-hugo-server&#34;&gt;5. Start the Hugo Server&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You start the &lt;em&gt;Hugo&lt;/em&gt; server by using the following command in Terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;hugo server -D
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;-D&lt;/code&gt; option means the server will also show any draft posts you may be writing. In this case, &lt;code&gt;my-first-post.md&lt;/code&gt; is a draft. If you look at the top of your &lt;code&gt;my-first-post.md&lt;/code&gt; file, you&amp;rsquo;ll see &lt;code&gt;draft: true&lt;/code&gt;, meaning this post has a &lt;em&gt;draft&lt;/em&gt; status. You publish the article by changing &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;. If you run the &lt;em&gt;Hugo&lt;/em&gt; server without &lt;code&gt;-D&lt;/code&gt;, your draft posts will not show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in your browser, visit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;http://localhost:1313/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voilà, your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hugo&lt;/em&gt; server is always checking your &lt;code&gt;blog&lt;/code&gt; folder for any changes that you make to any files and will update automatically whenever you make those changes. To stop the server at any time, just press &lt;code&gt;ctrl + c&lt;/code&gt; in the Terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concludes the first part in our three-part series in getting your site set up in Hugo. In your own time, have a look around the files that came with your theme, edit the &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; with your own information, try installing different themes, write a couple of posts, etc. The best way to learn is by having a play around yourself. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ll have found creating the site extremely easy, so don&amp;rsquo;t be worried about breaking anything. At this stage, you should be experimenting a little bit and if worse comes to worse, you can start over. Just make sure to protect your &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; folder, because again, this is where the bulk of your custom content is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check back in next time for the next part of this tutorial where we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into exactly how to have your site hosted on GitHub Pages. See you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>

    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

